Mss.B.R538
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 1906-1974
  - Gunnison, Olive M., November, 1954; Gunnison, R.M., Mrs.
  - Guppy, Nicholas, 1950
  - Hall, Robert W., June 14, 1911
  - Halloran, John L., December 1, 1961
  - Hamilton, Warren F., January, 1963
  - Handsfield, Hugh W., June, 1953
  - Hansell, Dorothy E., 1951, 1957
  - Hanson, Frank Blair, April, 1936
  - Harding, Charles B., 1967, 1970
  - Harper, E.A., October 12, 1937
  - Harper, J. Henry, October 7, 1948
  - Harper, R.A., October 9, 1937
  - Harrar, J. George, 1958, 1962
  - Harrison, Ross G., July, 1940
  - Hartley, Carl, August 7, 1928
  - Haskins, Caryl, 1963-1964
  - Hayward, H., 1917
  - Haworth, Leland J., August, 1963
  - Hedrick, E.R., 1937
  - Heim, Roger, 1959
  - Hemphill, Janice S., July, 1955
  - Henry, Barklie McKee, 1956, 1959
  - Herpers, Richard, January 27, 1960
  - Herring, Pendleton, December 21, 1962
  - Hess, Gertrude D., 1959; Hess, Ellwood E., Mrs.
  - Hicks, Caroline J., 1954; Hicks, Henry, Mrs.
  - Hildebrand, Earl M., 1961
  - Hill, A.V., 1929
  - Hill, Evelyn Collins, May 3, 1958
  - Hood, Marshall L., June 7, 1959
  - Hooker, Blanche Ferry, June, 1944; Hooker, Elon Huntington, Mrs.
  - Houston, W.V., September, 1952
  - Howland, Harold E., 1937, 1955
  - Hughes, Raymond M., January 1, 1938
  - Hunsacker, J.C., 1959, 1963
  - Hunt, Rachel, 1958; Hunt, Roy A., Mrs.
  - Hunter, S.H., March 3, 1961
  - Ingraham, Mark H., 1944
  - Institution Sillig, April 4, 1930
  - Jennings, Nell, 1958, 1967; Jennings, Alvin R., Mrs.
  - Jewett, Frank B., 1946-1947
    Includes correspondence regarding the National Academy of Science.
  - Johnson, Treat B., November 18, 1941
  - Johnston, J.B., 1930
  - Jones, J.S., February 28, 1916
  - Kavanagh, Frederick, 1943, 1963
  - Keck, David D., 1961, 1967
  - Keith, Arthur, January 22, 1929
  - Kelly, Harry C., 1960, 1963
  - Kelly, Neil, October 8, 1958
  - Kendall, Henry P., 1954
  - Kerr, Chester, November 13, 1959
  - Khan, Azhar Ali, April 26, 1955
  - King, Glen, February 28, 1967
  - Kirk, Grayson, 1957-1959
  - Kistiakowsky, G.B., December, 1959
  - Klein, Julius, October 11, 1949
  - Kline, George T., October 12, 1937
  - Knudson, Lewis, 1914-1916, 1937
  - Kohlberg, Alfred, December, 1956
  - Kramer, Paul J., November 5, 1937
  - Kraus, E.J., December 20, 1933
  - Krout, John A., December 20, 1957
  - Kunkel, L.O., October 23, 1937
  - Lam, H.J., 1949
  - Lamkin, Uel M., October 13, 1937
  - Larrimer, W.H., 1960
  - Lathrop, E.C., 1917
  - Lawrence, George H.M., 1958-1963
  - Leach, Henry Goddard, January 12, 1959
  - LeClerg, E.L., 1952
  - LeClerg, Robert E., July 1, 1952
  - Lehigh University, 1906-1911, 1937
  - Lehigh University Library, September 19, 1957
  - Lemon, Burt, December 7, 1937
  - Lewis, Clarence McK., 1937, 1958
  - Lewis, Edwin O., May 5, 1965
  - Lillie, Frank R., 1935-1937
  - Lindeberg, G., September 24, 1967
  - Linnean Society of London, September 5, 1962
  - Linton, Albert, May, 1963
  - The Little Forum, May 1, 1958
  - Livingston, B.E., 1916
  - Lloyd, John T. (Sam), 1916-1917, 1939, 1950
  - Lloyd, John Uri, 1917-1921
  - Loeb, Robert F., 1958-1960
  - Loehwing, Walter F., November, 1937
  - Lowdin, Per-Olov, August 6, 1963
  - Lowie, Robert H., May, 1932
  - Lundell, C.L., 1960
  - MacArthur, Douglas, March 4, 1948
  - MacDonald, D.F., February 12, 1937
  - Macelwane, J.B., October, 1937
  - MacFarguhan, Mary, December 11, 1940
  - Maneval, W.E., 1941-1954
  - Marceau, Henri, February 17, 1959
  - Marquat, W.F., September 5, 1947
  - Martin, Frank L., October, 1937
  - Matheson, R. Hardy, July, 1963
  - Mathias, Mildred E., September 15, 1960
  - Matze, Edwin B., July 3, 1959
  - Maynard, L.A., March, 1958
  - McClary, Ed, May 8, 1938
  - McNew, George L., 1958-1970
  - McVeigh, Ilda, January 14, 1970
  - Meid, G.D., August 4, 1949
  - Meredith, Constance, March 28, 1956; Meredith, Richard, Mrs.
  - Merrill, E.B., 1937
  - Metcalf, Haven, 1929
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art, March 25, 1945
  - Metzger, Karl E., 1958, 1961
  - Middlebush, F.A., 1930-1937
  - Mill, R.L., March 26, 1930
  - Miller, Walter, June 11, 1930
  - Mirsky, Alfred E., 1963
  - Mixsell, Charlotte Mallory, 1953; Mallory, Harold R., Mrs.
  - Moe, Henry Allen, 1948-1963
  - Montagne, H. de la, 1937-1958
  - Montague, Gilbert H., 1957-1959
  - Moore, George T., October 12, 1937
  - Morrison, Thomas H., October, 1952
  - Moseley, Frederick S., Jr., January 20, 1958
  - Moulton, F.R., August, 1943
  - Mugi, Magbool Ahmed, February, 1955
  - Mumford, F.B., 1929-1930
  - Murnane, George, May 9, 1955
  - National Academy of Sciences, October 21, 1948
  - National Memorial Park, 1952
  - Nelson, Earl F., November, 1937
  - Netherlands Indies Government, June 2, 1940
  - New York Academy of Medicine--Microbiology, March 10, 1961
  - New York Botanical Garden, 1950-1958
  - Nichols, G.E., November 30, 1937
  - Nichols, Roy F., January 13, 1959
  - Nishina, Yoshio, 1951
  - Northrop, John H., 1952, 1970
  - Nyabongo, A., January, 1953
  - Odintsoya, Catherine N., March 15, 1960
  - Overbeek, J. van, May 17, 1960
  - Overton, J.B., April 16, 1914
  - Page, Curtis, 1958
  - Pakistan Association for the Advancement of Science, March 19, 1955
  - Peale, Harriet, February 15, 1958
  - Pearl, Raymond, November 27, 1929
  - Pennekamp, John D., 1962
  - Pepper, O.H. Perry, 1959
  - Pfeiffer, A., November 11, 1929
  - Philadelphia Contributionship, May 3, 1956
  - Pickett, F.L., October 25, 1937
  - Pierpont Morgan Library, Undated
  - Place, Angela Wood, October 10, 1958
  - Poehlman, J.M., January, 1956
  - Pratt, Harriet, 1947-1948; Pratt, Harold Irving, Mrs.
  - Prentice, Alta Rockefeller, 1949-1957
  - President's Science Advisory Committee, January 4, 1960
  - Rappaport, Jacob, 1949
  - Rautenstrauch, Walter, October 18, 1937
  - Reeder, John R., January 27, 1959
  - Remick, J. Gould, 1961-1962
  - Richards, Alfred N., 1948-1949
  - Rickett, H.W., March 13, 1930
  - Riker, A.J., 1959-1961
  - Rivera, Rudolph, February 23, 1955
  - Robbins, Christine, 1928-1947; Robbins, William Jacob, Mrs.
  - Robbins, Christine, 1951-1970; Robbins, William Jacob, Mrs.
  - Robbins, Eliza, April 28, 1955
  - Robbins, Frederick Woods, 1923-1929, 1937
  - Robbins, Frederick Woods, Mrs., 1923-1929, 1947
  - Robertson, William B., Jr., 1963
  - Robyns, W., 1952, 1965
  - Rockefeller, David, December 1, 1961
  - Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research, 1954
  - Rockefeller, Peggy, 1969-1970; Rockefeller, David, Mrs.
  - Roderick, Hilliard, December 18, 1962
  - Roe, Anne, 1970
  - Rogers, M. Robert, Undated
  - Roijen, J.H. van, May 4, 1954
  - Rose, Alfred L., 1961
  - Rosselot, R.E., January 11, 1955
  - Rothschild, Carole Wesbury, December 21, 1961
  - Rothschild, Walter N., December 16, 1958
  - Rowan, E.C., 1955
  - Royal Botanic Gardens, Kew, September 3, 1962
  - Rufi, John, October 14, 1937
  - Rusk, Dean, November 13, 1969
  - Russell, William F., December 6, 1937
  - Saeger, Albert, 1937
  - Saudek, Robert, May 28, 1959
  - Sawin, Edith W., 1956-1958; Sawin, Melvin E., Mrs.
  - Schaefer, Vincent J., August 6, 1963
  - Schilling, H.S., December 18, 1962
  - Schramm, J.R., 1956-1958
  - Schramm, Mildred W.S., May, 1955
  - Schreiner, Oswald, 1917-1919
  - Scientific Advisory Group (Japan), 1945-1947
  - Scientific Research Institute, January 11, 1951
  - Scott, John, July 25, 1971
  - Searls, Fred, Jr., 1959-1962
  - Sears, Paul B., 1955
  - Seaver, Fred J., December, 1958
  - Seinor, Maud, August 3, 1970
  - Severance, Harry O., November, 1937
  - Shanor, Leland, November 13, 1958
  - Short, Lloyd M., November 4, 1937
  - Shryock, Richard H., 1959-1961
  - Siddiqui, Salimuzzaman, 1955
  - Sinnott, Edmund W., 1937, 1963
  - Skinner, J.C., September 19, 1952
  - Skoog, Folke, 1970
  - Slate, George L., February 23, 1970
  - Slater, J.E., February, 1963
  - Smiley, Nixon, 1958-1965
  - Smith, A.C., 1960-1963
  - Smith, Howard E., August, 1950
  - Smith, J.J. Pringle, 1952
  - Smith, Tom K., 1937, 1956
  - Smith, Walter L., Jr., May 4, 1956
  - Stadler, L.J., March 20, 1946
  - Stakman, E.C., 1946
  - Stanley, Wendall M., 1957
  - Steere, William C., 1959
  - Steinbach, H. Burr, 1960-1961
  - Stern, Kurt G., November 5, 1941
  - Swan, Joseph R., 1944-1963
  - Tashjian, Robert J., 1961-1963
  - Tatlow, Richard H. III, 1961
  - Taylor, George, February, 1959
  - Taylor, Louise, May 25, 1967
  - Thach, Charles C., 1915-1916
  - Thomas, Stanley, October 22, 1937
  - Thompson, Will H., October 13, 1937
  - Tisdale, Frederick M., 1929-1930
  - Tisdale, W.E., 1929
  - Transeau, Edgar Nelson, October, 1929
  - Trotter, Ide P., November, 1937
  - Trustees of atoms for peace award, Undated
  - Trytten, M.H., March, 1955
  - Tutt?, Undated
  - University of Missouri, 1923-1933
  - University of Missouri, 1934-1959
  - University of New Hampshire, 1944
  - Vincent, George E., June 28, 1929
  - Virtanen, A.J., May 7, 1969
  - Wadsworth, Frank H., May 16, 1960
  - Wahl, Charlotte K., March, 1958; Wahl, Manfred, Mrs.
  - Waksman, Selman A., May 23, 1958
  - Wallace, Henry A., 1954-1959
  - Wallace, Ilo, December 30, 1956
  - Waller, Wilhelmine K., June 24, 1959; Waller, Thomas M., Mrs.
  - Walsh, John K., October 14, 1937
  - Walsh, T.J., 1952
  - War Department, 1947
  - Warnshuis, A.L., Mrs., May 27, 1958
  - Wasson, R. Gordon, 1958, 1963
  - Wasson, Robert G., June 10, 1963
  - Waterman, Alan T., 1958-1967
  - Weaver, Warren, February 19, 1959
  - Webster, Charles D., December, 1957
  - Weiss, Ulrich, 1963, 1970
  - Went, F.W., 1960
  - Whetzel, H.H., January 13, 1919
  - White, Philip R., 1930
  - Whitehill, Walter Muir, March 11, 1970
  - Whitlock, Francis Beacham, Mrs., May, 1958
  - Wickenden, Mira and Homer, May 27, 1958
  - Wiegand, K.M., January 8, 1916
  - Wiggans, R.G., December 27, 1937
  - Wildish, James E., October 11, 1937
  - Williams, R.R., December 1, 1938
  - Willits, Joseph H., March, 1960
  - Wilson, Dorothy, Undated
  - Wilson, Edwin B., 1942-May, 1949
    Includes correspondence on activities within the Office of Scientific Research and Development and the National Academy of Sciences, and surveys of the effects of World War II on academic science.
  - Wilson, Edwin B., August, 1949-1953
  - Wilson, Edwin B., 1954-1962
  - Wirth, Conrad L., December 16, 1963
  - Wister Association, Undated
  - Wolfle, Dael, 1955, 1962
  - Women's National Farm and Garden Association, Inc., April 6, 1960
  - Women's Theodore Roosevelt Memorial Association, Undated
  - Woodward, Carol, October 7, 1948
  - Wright, Fred E., 1940-1948
  - Zirkle, Raymond, 1937, 1959
  - Zwemer, Raymund L., May 9, 1949
- Series II. Articles and notes, 1896-1974
  - Advantages of the large university, 1939
  - Advisory committee on fellowships of the National Research Council, January 23, 1933
  - American Association for the advancement of science, December 30, 1920
  - American Philosophical Society--committee on publications, May 20, 1960
  - Biographical sketch, February 6, 1974
  - Board of National Research Fellowships in the biological sciences, January 1, 1931
  - Cellulose Digestion-notes, 1915-1916
  - Conference on Tropical Botanical Problems, May, 1960
  - Constitutional Convention of 1787, 1908
  - The corn field, April, 1905
  - Crop Ecology, 1912-1915; Duggar, Benjamin M., (Benjamin Minge), 1872-1956
  - DAS/CMS/63.34--notes, June 24, 1963
  - Delegate--Atlantic Congress, January 24, 1919
  - Diary note, February 25, 1963
    Meeting on possible Ford Foundation activity in area of problems and opportunities created by impact of science and technology.
  - Diary of European Trip, 1928
  - Duel in the animal world, December 8, 1904
  - Evolution of botanical research in New York City--notes, Undated
  - Fellowships in the Natural Sciences, 1928-1930
  - Future of plant physiology, Undated
  - Gibberellic acid and the reversal of adult hedera to a juvenile state, 1957
  - Graduation, November 12, 1906
  - Heraclitus--first term philosophy, 1909-1910
  - Institut Oceanographique, 1925
  - International Histological Conference--notes, August, 1930
  - Japan--agriculture, etc., December 9, 1947
    Speech given by Dr. Robbins to New York farmers at Metropolitan Club.
  - Japanese science, August 22, 1957
    Visit to Dr. Makino at his home in a suburb of Tokyo.
  - Lehigh University--notebooks, 1906-1910
  - Military service, 1917-1918
  - Gilbert H. Montague--will, 1959
  - Municipal government in the United States with reference to the commission plan, 1910
    Thesis presented to the faculty of Lehigh University for the degree of Bachelor of Arts.
  - National Academy of Science, 1959
  - National Research Council, 1936
  - Newspaper clippings, 1917-1918
  - New York Farmers, December 9, 1947
    198th dinner, Metropolitan Club.
  - New York State College of Agriculture--Cornell University, March, 1912
    Department of Plant Physiology, Crop Ecology, course given by B.M. Duggar--notes.
  - Notebooks, 1899-1906
  - Nutrient requirements of fungi, December 27, 1947
    Dr. Robbin's speech at Chicago AAAS meeting.
  - Outline of the process and art of learning for the classroom teacher, 1926; Robbins, Frederick Woods,1860-1939.
  - Pakistan trip--random notes, 1955
  - Panama Canal, 1906
  - Photographs, 1933-1956
  - Place of horticulture in the life of the nation, Undated
  - Plant Pathologist, February 19, 1919
  - Plant physiology--lectures, October, 1915
  - Poland--notes, 1929-1930
  - Pride, Undated
  - Quadrature of the circle, Undated
  - Report cards, 1896-1910
  - Frederick Woods Robbins--chronology, 1860-1939
  - Scope of the Department of Public Instruction, 1923
  - Seventh Pakistan Science Conference, February 19, 1955
  - Significance of art in life, 1910
    Psychology, First term.
  - Soil Biochemist, April 22, 1919
  - Substitution of means for ends, May 29, 1936
    Ideas by F.W. Robbins. Words by W.J. Robbins.
  - Sugar, Undated
  - Tariff, Undated
  - Towanda Public School, 1898-1900
  - Trip to England, 1928-1929
  - Trip to England, Ireland and Belgium, February 17-24, 1930
  - Trip to Germany, January 21-25, 1929
  - Trip to Germany, Czechoslovakia, Austria, Italy, March 11-24, 1930
  - Trip to Germany, Denmark, Sweden, and Norway, April 30-May 10, 1930
  - Trip to Germany and Switzerland, January 21-30, 1930
  - Trip to Holland and England, August 4-21, 1930
  - Trip to Holland and Germany, September 5-18, 1929
  - Trip to Holland, Germany, Poland, Czechoslovakia, Austria, Switzerland, September 12-21, 1928
  - Trip to Italy, 1928-1929
  - Trip to Italy, Yugoslavia, Austria, Czechoslovakia, March 24-April 27, 1927
  - Trip to London and Oxford, February 12-14, 1929
  - Trip to Plymouth, England, March 29-30, 1930
  - Trip to Poland, Romania, Bulgaria, Hungary, Yugoslavia, June 11-30, 1930
  - Trip to Poland, Russia, October 21-31, 1929
  - Trip to Roscoff, July 21-22, 1929
  - Trip to Russia, November 1-5, 1929
  - Trip to Switzerland, Czechoslovakia, Poland, and Germany, April, 1929
  - Trip to Zurich, Vienna, Munich, and Strasbourg, November 12-16, 1928